# Naveed Gujral

in www.linkedin.com/in/naveed-gujral



naveedgujral.co.uk

Nottingham, UK

### About

I am a ex-Industrial Designer transitioning into a digital design/developer role after completing the Northcoders Bootcamp in Fullstack software development. With over 5 years experience designing and developing physical products for a number of clients I am now looking for a role where I can develop digital products and services. I have hands-on experience in Front-end and Back-end development using React, Express.js, SQL as well other technologies. Over the years I have developed a skillset that includes Product Design/Development and Project Management alongside inter-disciplinary communication, technical documentation and client relations. I am committed to continous professional development and collaboration in teams with a variety of disciplines to achieve our common goals.

### Experience

# Freelance Web Developer | Reine Creative

Mar 2024 - Aug 2024

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Tailwind, React, Node.js, Next.js, Framer-Motion, Email.js, Vimeo, Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop

Designed and built a website for a freelance film-maker who trades under the name Reine Creative.

- Designed and developed the website using various technologies
- Consulted on the design of the brand and how it can best communicate the brand values
- Designed the logo
- Advised the client on how to produce responsive videos to be used in the landing and portfolio section
- Produced graphics to be used in the website

# Freelance Industrial Designer | Various Clients

Dec 2016 - Present

Continued to work as an Industrial Designer using the network I had formed during my apprenticeship. As a freelancer I provided the same services I provided in my previous role. I am still contacted to work on industrial design projects although I am now looking to pivot towards the design or development of digital products and services.

# Industrial Designer | Techstyle-Europe

Dec 2013 - Oct 2016

Completed an apprenticeship in industrial design and continued to work there as a full time industrial designer for a further year. My role had a heavy emphasis on design for manufacture and I have worked on a wide range of products for a variety of sectors.

- Designed and developed new products
- Presented the status of projects to various stakeholders including clients
- Managed client relationships
- Produced technical documentation needed to begin production
- Managed projects from conception to production.
- Acted as the liason with third parties.
- Applied for Intellectual Property Protection on behalf of the client and produced the documents needed for an application.

### Skills

### Languages:

- Javascript Typescript
- · HTML · CSS · SQL
- · C++ · Python · GLSL

### Testing:

• TDD • Jest • Supertest

#### Back-end:

- SQL postgreSQL Express.js
- Seeding & Migrations

#### Front-end:

- · React · React Native · Tailwind
- Three.js React Fiber p5.js
- · React Spring · Framer-Motion

#### Technologies:

- · Node.js · Express.js · GitHub
- Plasmo Next.js Supabase
- Firebase
  Cloudinary

### Design tools:

- · Photoshop · Indesign · Illustrator
- Figma Blender

#### Additional skills:

- · Product/Service Design
- Branding Graphic Design
- UI/UX Design IP protection
- Client Relationship Management
- · Rendering · Project Management
- Parametric 3D Modelling
- · Algorithm Aided 3D Modelling
- · Embedded Systems Development

# Naveed Gujral

in www.linkedin.com/in/naveed-gujral

□ naveedgujral93@gmail.com

github.com/NaveedGujral

maveedgujral.co.uk

Nottingham, UK

# Personal Projects

#### Visual

Mar 2024 - Present

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Tailwind, React, Node.js, Next.js, Plasmo, Three.js, GLSL, Figma, Illustrator

Worked in partnership with a software developer I trained with at Northcoders to build a google chrome extension that visualises audio in 3D from a tab. The project is currently in open-beta and we are currently user testing.

- Developed the visualisers using custom shaders written in GLSL (based on the C programming language)
- Front-end development using Plasmo a framework based on React, similar to Next.js, for developing Google Chrome extensions
- Collaborated on the development of the UI/UX using wireframes.
- Designed the Logo and developed the Branding

#### **PlotTwist**

Dec 2023 - Mar 2024

React Native, Javascript, CSS, Node.js, SQL, SupaBase, Google Books API, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

A mobile app developed during my time at Northcoders as part of a 6 person team for our final project. The app allows for the user to swap books with other users. This project was continued after completion of the bootcamp and taken up to a minimum viable prototype stage. During the project I was part of the Front-end sub-team although I occasionally assisted the Back-end sub-team.

- Worked on the development of the front-end using React Native
- Worked with members of the back-end sub-team on implementing key features such as the swapping functionality and messaging.
- Assisted the Back-end sub-team with the initial set-up of the database
- Collaborated on the development of the UI/UX using wireframes.
- Co-designed the branding with the front-end sub-team
- Designed the logo with feedback from the team.

For more information on each project my portfolio can be found at www.naveedgujral.co.uk

References can be provided upon request.

# Education

#### Northcoders

Oct 2023 - Jan 2024

 Software Development Bootcamp in Javascript

### University of the West of England Sep 2018 - Jul 2021

• Bsc Product Design Technology 2:1

### Barnsley College

Jan 2013 - Jan 2015

 Product design apprenticeship training provider

# Heckmondwike Grammar School 2007 - 2011

GCSE/A-Levels

### Interests

#### Tinkering:

I like to experiment with CAD, 3D Printing and Arduino. I enjoy the process of coming up with an idea and seeing it out, solving problems along the way. Seeing a project come to life after all the time invested is always very rewarding.

### Life Drawing:

I have always liked drawing and I find life drawing is a nice way to relax away from screens.

### Muay Thai:

To keep fit I train in Muay Thai. The martial art has a vast amount of theory and techniques to learn and refine which is the reason it has kept my interest for such a long time. The discipline and the need to continuously develop has shaped my attitude as a professional.